Summary

I am a software engineer that has been building Java applications professionally for seven years. Currently, I work for SwingAI. My most recent project is Swing Index, an on-demand mobile golf app. I also support LifeJourney, building web applications used by hundreds of students on a daily basis. Java is my most proficient language, though I also work with Javascript on the front end using AngularJS and have used Node.js for a few side projects, as well as WordPress.

Relevant Experience

Swing Index

LifeJourney / Swing AI

2018 - Present

- Software Engineer
 - Worked on a small team of 5 to build the application from the ground up
 - Developed entities and business logic using Spring Framework and Hibernate
 - Provided backend services to iOS and Android applications via RESTful web services
 - Responsible for building the instructor scoring dashboard using AngularJS
 - Implemented an asynchronous messaging system using Apache Kafka
 - Worked closely with a designer to develop and maintain dozens of marketing websites

LifeJourney.us

Software Engineer

LifeJourney / Swing AI

2014 - Present

- Built and maintained web application in Java using Spring and Hibernate, capable of handling thousands of concurrent users by means of NGINX load balancing and multiple Tomcat servers
- Developed and maintained frontend in AngularJS
- Maintained 80% unit test coverage using JUnit and Jasmine on the back and front ends respectively,
 as well built integration tests using Geb and REST Assured
- Wrote migration scripts in Groovy that managed the migration of multiple versions of the application to satisfy multiple clients concurrently
- Built deployment scripts in Ruby using Capistrano to manage the deployment of the application to multiple environments

MatOnto Materials Science Framework

iNovex Information Systems

Software Developer

2012-2014

- Developed RESTful web services using Groovy on Grails that orchestrated CKAN data publishing
- Built ontologies serialized in RDF to enable federated SPARQL queries across multiple data sources
- Designed Accumulo powered Graph Data store to handle high volume integrated data

Skills

Languages: Java (Proficient), Javascript (Proficient), Groovy (Proficient), Kotlin (Familiar), Node.js (Competent), Ruby (Competent), HTML/CSS (Proficient), Sass (Proficient), SQL (Competent)

Frameworks & Libraries: Spring (Proficient), Hibernate (Proficient), Angular JS (Proficient), React (Familiar), Vue.js (Familiar), Bootstrap (Proficient), Gulp (Proficient), Webpack (Proficient)

Certifications: Oracle Certified Associate, Java SE 7 Programmer

Volunteer: Open Source Contributor for Twitter Bootstrap, Designer and Developer of https://usa505.org

Education

Connecticut College

New London, CT

B.A. Major Computer Science, Minor Economics (GPA 3.28)

2008 - 2012

 Relevant Courses: Computational Intelligence, Artificial Intelligence, Networks, Algorithms, Data Structures, Knowledge Representation and Reasoning, Software Engineering Methodologies